<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>devops on Hello World</title><link>https://deadlysyn.com/blog/tags/devops/</link><description>Recent content in devops on Hello World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://deadlysyn.com/blog/tags/devops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lean AWS IAM</title><link>https://deadlysyn.com/blog/posts/lean-aws-iam/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://deadlysyn.com/blog/posts/lean-aws-iam/</guid><description>Part of DevOps culture is avoiding tickets when automation can provide lower-friction alternatives. Similarly, the SRE mindset seeks to eliminate toil. We also know from experience that the most effective Agile teams are granted a high level of autonomy.
IAM is a routine stumbling block to autonomy. Teams need an &amp;ldquo;appropriate&amp;rdquo; level of access to do their job. That often turns into waiting on tickets, with another team twiddling bits to unblock development.</description></item><item><title>Introducing Retriever</title><link>https://deadlysyn.com/blog/posts/retriever/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://deadlysyn.com/blog/posts/retriever/</guid><description>The AWS SDK is great. Writing boilerplate for simple tasks is&amp;hellip; Well, you have better things to do.
Whether creating CLIs or services, one task I routinely encounter is secrets management. With AWS, I might use Secrets Manager (advanced features such as versioning simplify programmatic rotation) or Parameter Store (cost savings at scale, works great for injecting container environment).
I find myself repeating boilerplate (load configuration, create client, retrieve secret):</description></item><item><title>Go Datadog Client</title><link>https://deadlysyn.com/blog/posts/datadog-client/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://deadlysyn.com/blog/posts/datadog-client/</guid><description>I recently found myself wrapping ChatOps around a CI/CD pipeline to manage scheduled downtime in DataDog (avoiding SLO impact for planned work). For astute readers wondering why this wasn&amp;rsquo;t a direct API call &amp;ndash; I tend to (ab)use CI as a generic task runner (has an API, secret store, etc).
I wanted to identify resources using labels (team:foo, service:bar). Sounded simple enough. It&amp;rsquo;s been over a month, so things may have improved, but documentation and available clients provided numerous ways to manage downtime beside tags.</description></item></channel></rss>