<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>containers on Hello World</title><link>https://deadlysyn.com/blog/tags/containers/</link><description>Recent content in containers on Hello World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://deadlysyn.com/blog/tags/containers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Contain Yourself</title><link>https://deadlysyn.com/blog/posts/contain-yourself/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://deadlysyn.com/blog/posts/contain-yourself/</guid><description>Clone the project repo to follow along&amp;hellip;
In part one of this series we walked through using Docker to containerize a simple Node.js app and verified our shiny new container worked as expected. Unfortunately, containers aren&amp;rsquo;t much use if we can&amp;rsquo;t get them deployed to start delighting users with the sheer awesomeness of our brilliant code.
In the container world, the path to production involves some sort of registry&amp;hellip; While it sounds fancy, a registry isn&amp;rsquo;t much different from the simple web servers you historically used to host RPMs or DEBs (essentially just another tool to help you maintain the ITIL concept of a Definitive Software Library.</description></item><item><title>Thinking Inside the Box</title><link>https://deadlysyn.com/blog/posts/thinking-inside-the-box/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://deadlysyn.com/blog/posts/thinking-inside-the-box/</guid><description>Clone the project repo to follow along&amp;hellip;
This is going to be another multi-part series&amp;hellip; I don&amp;rsquo;t want to get too far ahead of myself, but the end goal is shipping a Node.js app using Amazon Web Service&amp;rsquo;s Elastic Container Service (ECS). We have to crawl before we can walk (or run an app), so this first article will cover the basics of getting a simple Node app containerized (feel free to plug in whatever app you want).</description></item></channel></rss>